# Abhijit Hoskeri - Resume

abhijithoskeri@gmail.com +91 998 668 4203

# **Objective**

To perform challenging work that will utilize my technical and analytical skill on the Linux/Unix platform to create useful applications and technology.

# **Summary**

I have been working for over 5 years. Currently I am working on virtualization and storage optimization applications. Before this I have worked on the development and maintenance of the deepOfix Mail Server, a Linux distribution meant to run email servers.

## **Technical Skills**

## **Programming Languages**

C, Perl, Python, Ruby, Scheme

## **Development**

- Knowledge of UNIX system programming (System calls, basic library functions, networking, etc)
- Linux kernel filesystems (ext2 and ext3) and device-mapper (dm) driver internals.
- · Excellent understanding of the UNIX and Linux ecosystem
  - Excellent knowledge of Bash scripting and automation.
  - o Experience with installation and maintainence of Email server infrastructure.
  - Linux firewall, VPN and router configuration.
- Development of distributed server applications with python and erlang.
- ORM (Object-Relation Mapping) frameworks like Storm.
- Experience with the MVC (Model-View-Controller) model of application development (Django, Sinatra).
- Packaging software and maintenance of such packages. (Debian and RPM packages)

#### **Tools**

- Version control systems including Git, Mercurial, Subversion, CVS.
- · Build software including make, GNU Autoconf.
- Project management with Trac, Bugzilla, Request-Tracker, Jira, etc.

# **Work Experience**

## Atlantis Computing Pvt. Ltd. (Aug 2008 till present)

- Worked on development of a deduplicating filesystem based on ext2/ext3 kernel module in Linux. The ext2 filesystem
  was modified to perform deduplication of incoming data to eliminate redundant block writes and improve performance
  of virtual machines by 500%.
- Development of features and bug fixing on the core of the product, which is a python based distributed server
  application to manage and enhance the performance of virtual machine disk images.
- Worked on converting the product from a centralized architecture to a distributed architecture to support larger scale of users and workload.
- Built a Linux live-cd based installer for the product. This involved development of modules for setting up VMware ESX
  server and configuration of virtual machines and applications. The installer was built as a python application which itself
  ran on a virtual machine.
- Wrote a Windows MFC application to monitor and report health of Virtual Machines. This application runs on user virtual machines and responds to commands sent over a TCP/IP socket.
- Implemented a high availability solution for failover of services provided by the product using heartbeat, DRBD (Distributed Replicated Block Device) and OCFS2 (Oracle Clustered File System)

## DeepRoot Linux Private Limited. (Sep 2006 to July 2008)

- Support, development and maintenance of the deepOfix Mail Server, a GNU/Linux distribution built to run email services.
- Rebuilt the entire installer and package set over a period of six months to make the entire system more manageable and upgradable.
- Fixed bugs and added features to various open source software used by the product, and contributed them up-stream.
- Headed the support team, comprising four people to provide incident support and customizations for the above product and allied services. Responsible for 200 servers in my support role.
- Support and maintenance of OpenVPN VPN installations.
- Wrote patches for internal use for software such as Qmail, Dovecot, etc.

## Maspro IT Solutions Private Limited (Dec 2005 to Aug 2006)

- Worked as an on-site engineer performing Systems Administration tasks, first at EthicSoft, Jayanagar in Bangalore and then at Resolve India, a division of Tally Solutions.
- At EthicSoft, was responsible for the corporate LAN, including email services, firewalls, and the test servers for various projects at the company.
- Implemented a version control system using CVS. Created an automated commit-compile-build-deploy system on the
  above test servers. Consulted on development of a firewall/gateway security appliance for one of the projects at
  EthicSoft.
- At Resolve India, I was responsible for the maintenance of the LAN, Windows based terminal servers, firewall, email servers etc, as a Systems Administrator.

## **Educational Background**

- B.E. in Industrial and Production Engineering, from Basaveshwara Engg. College, Bagalkot, Karnataka in 2005.
- Participated, and won prizes in Quiz competitions both at the college level as well at inter- collegiate competitions. I
  represented my engineering college at the sixth VTU Youth Festival held at BIET, Davanagere, in 2005.
- After graduation, I took a six month course in 'Advanced Unix Programming' at Uttara, at Rajajinagar in Bangalore.
- Languages known: Kannada, English, Hindi

#### **Other Interests**

I play the Tabla. I have cleared the first level (Prathama) examinations on the Tabla. I have also given accompaniment on the Tabla at several light music events.

## **Personal Details**

Full name Abhijit Pralhad Hoskeri
Father's name Pralhad B. Hoskeri
Date of birth 14th November, 1983
Email abhijithoskeri@gmail.com

Cell phone 99866 84203 Home phone 0836 2440927

#### **Declaration**

I hereby submit that the information given above is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.